加州 萨克拉门托县北部
-=耐卡影音论坛=-
www.ncar.cc/bbs
欣赏更多精彩美剧
字幕源自Internet
Stay calm.
保持冷静
Do that, nothing can go wrong. Got it?
按计划来 不会出错的 明白吗?
Yeah, we got it.
嗯 明白了
Hi, good to see you again.
嗨 真高兴又见到你了
Uh, yes, that time of the year.
又到时候了
I have to get my shoes resoled.
我得换个鞋底
Uh, put. Put.
行 拿来看看 放上来
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
嗯 好的 好的
Right there. Got just a... a hole there.
就在那 有个... 有个小洞呢
Everybody, get down!
所有人都趴下!
This is a robbery! Get down from behind the counter.
抢劫! 从柜台后面出来 趴下!
Get down here! Now!
快趴下! 快点!
Get down!
趴下!
- Down!  - Oh.
- 趴下!  - 天呐
Get down! Get down on the ground!
趴下! 趴到地上!
Nobody do anything stupid!
都别乱动!
Cameras. Move.
有监控 去搞定摄像头
I want to cell phones kicked
你们马上把手机
into the center of the room right now.
都扔到大厅中间来
Let's see 'em!
快点扔过来!
Mm.
嗯
Name.
报上名来
Still Jane.
还写Jane吧
Jane.
好的 Jane
Thank you.
多谢
And, uh,
请问
how long do you think that'll be?
多久能换好啊?
We'll see.
看情况吧
Okay.
好吧
Good to see you, too.
我也很高兴见到你
Everybody's gonna go home to their families
如果你们不做蠢事的话
if they don't do anything stupid.
所有人都能毫发无伤地回家去
Who here can open the vault?
这里有谁能打开金库的?
I can. I can.
我 我可以
Get up! Get in the back!
起来! 到后面去!
Get the bags.
拿着袋子
Go!
快点!
Open it.
快打开
Hey. Kill it.
嘿 遮上那个摄像头
Here. Fill it.
拿着 装满
Fill it.
装满这个袋子
What's taking him so long?
他怎么磨叽这么久?
We don't need these.
不需要你来弄了
Count to a hundred.
数到一百
One,
一
two,
二
three...
三...
What the hell was that?
该死的 怎么回事?
Let's go!
走吧!
There's a cop.
那儿有个警察
Oh.
怎么了
- I think you need a little lie down.  - Oh. Oh. Oh.
- 我觉得你应该躺下来  - 天呐 晕了
Just have a little rest here.
在这休息会吧
I think I might faint.
我觉得我要晕倒了
There we go. Just put your head down there.
躺下吧 头就靠地上吧
超感神探 第五季第3集
Okay. Thanks.
行了 多谢
Three men hit the vault in the back for a million in cash.
3名男子闯入后面的保险柜劫走了一百万现金
The shot killed an assistant manager.
打死了一名副经理
Any witnesses?
有目击证人吗?
Lots, but they're not much help.
有很多 但都帮不上忙
The robbers were wearing masks.
劫匪戴着面具
They also blacked out the cameras with spray paint,
而且用喷漆屏蔽了摄像头
but I'm pulling the footage.
不过我已经在设法提取图像了
Where's Jane?
Jane在哪儿?
Inside.
在里面
Is that a friend of the victim?
那是受害人的朋友吗?
Fiancee. Works in the bank.
是他未婚妻 也在银行工作
Hey.
嘿
Nice shoes.
鞋子不错
Uh, yes, uh, loaners.
呃 是不错 可惜是借来的
Mine are in getting repaired.
我的鞋子送去修了
How long is that gonna take?
要修多久?
We'll see. The, uh...
看情况吧 呃...
cobbler fainted.
鞋匠吓晕了
Are you coming?
你也进来看看吗?
Meh.
不了
It's a little cramped in there.
里面太挤了
No expended casings in here. Any outside?
这里没有弹壳 外面有吗?
Found 2. Both 9-millimeter.
找到了2个 都是9毫米的
Witnesses say six shots were fired outside,
目击者说外面开了6枪
so one of the shooters must've been using a revolver.
所以他们中肯定有一个人用的是左轮手枪
Let me know what the M.E. says
鉴证科从受害人体内取出子弹后
when he pulls the slug from the victim.
告诉我他们怎么说的
You got anything?
你有发现了?
Maybe. I just spoke with a SAC P.D. detective
算是吧 刚刚和萨克拉门托警察局探员聊过
who thinks this robbery's connected
他认为这次劫案应该
with three others committed in the past six months.
和过去六个月里的另外三起有关
In all of them, two, sometimes three masked men,
这些案件中 都是2个或者3个戴面具的男子
took out the security cameras, passed up the teller drawers,
消除监控录像 越过出纳柜台
and went straight for the vault, just like these guys.
直接去抢金库 就跟今天这些人一样
How many victims in the other robberies?
其他案件中有几个受害人?
None. He's the first.
没有 他是第一个
Did SAC P.D. finish their search of the bank?
萨克拉门托警察局搜完银行没有?
Almost. Nothing so far.
差不多搜完了 至今毫无发现
Okay. Here's how we're gonna run this.
好吧 我们接下来这么做
You coordinate the witness interviews
你负责联系证人录口供
and tell Rigsby to pull the case files from the other robberies.
然后让Rigsby调出另几件案子的档案出来
I want to know if this is the same guys.
我想知道是不是同一批人
All right.
好的
This is Lisbon.
我是Lisbon探员
Cho. Was the safe deposit vault open when you got here?
Cho 你们到现场的时候保险箱是开着的吗?
Yeah. Why?
是的 怎么了?
Just curious.
好奇而已
Yes, sir. I will be right there.
好的 我马上就到
That was Bertram. I gotta go.
Bertram打来的 我得走了
Bank robberies belong to the FBI.
银行劫案归联邦调查局管
This case is ours.
这个案子归我们管
And tell me, why does the CBI continue to encroach
麻烦你告诉我 为什么加州调查局又来
on our jurisdiction?
侵犯我们的查案权利?
We were on site first.
我们最先到达现场
It's not our fault if you're late off the mark.
你们来迟了又不是我们的错
Agent Lisbon, Agent Mancini has a valid point
Lisbon探员呀 Mancinl探员在管辖权这个问题上
- regarding jurisdiction.  - Thank you.
- 真是一针见血  - 多谢夸奖
Sir, the crime my team and I are investigating
头儿 我和我的组员们正在调查的
is a crime of murder.
是谋杀案
A murder committed during a bank robbery.
那也是银行劫案过程中的谋杀案
The murder supersedes the crime of armed robbery.
谋杀案凌驾于持枪抢劫之上
So our investigation takes priority.
所以我们有权优先调查权
You're more than welcome to investigate
不过还是欢迎你们在我们谋杀案破案之后
after we close the murder.
接着来调查
Assuming you do.
假如你是这么认为的话
You know what they say about assuming things. It makes...
你知道他们都是怎么想的 这会...
- I know exactly what...  - All right. That's enough.
- 我当然知道那是...  - 好了 吵够了吧
Agent Mancini, Agent Lisbon and her team will take point
Mancini探员 Lisbon探员和她的小组
in the murder investigation.
先负责谋杀案的调查
In the meantime, you will have full access to all case files.
在此期间 你有权查看任何相关资料
Agreed?
都同意吗?
Hey. We have a personal problem?
嘿 我们有什么私人恩怨吗?
Personal problem?
什么私人恩怨?
You act like you don't like me,
你似乎很不喜欢我
like I killed your pet tortoise or something.
像我弄死了你的宠物龟一样
What, are we in high school?
扯淡吧 我们这是在高中吗?
You lost the most important witness we've ever had
你在红约翰案件中弄丢了我们最重要的
in the Red John case,
目击证人
and now you wonder why I won't make nice?
你还有脸来问我为什么对你没好脸色?
I didn't lose Lorelel Martins
我没有弄丢Lorelel Martins
and I want her back just as badly as you do.
我也跟你一样强烈希望她能回来
And generally speaking, when people act like
一般来说 每当人们表现得出不喜欢我的样子
they don't like me, it's because they really do.
那都是因为他们很喜欢我
They just don't want to admit it.
他们只是不愿承认而已
Yeah. No.
不 好吧 我承认
I don't like you.
我不喜欢你
You'll have the case files by the end of the day.
今天结束时就把档案给你们
Listen, there's this poker game we got going on.
嘿 我们要打扑克牌
It's a friendly game, mostly law enforcement,
友谊赛 大部分都是法院的人
State Department, FBI.
还有国务院和联邦调查局的
You want in?
想来参加吗?
Maybe. When?
也许吧 什么时候?
I'll call you with the details.
回头打给你详谈
Good luck with the case. Hope you find your man.
祝你破案顺利 早日找到凶手
All right.
好的
You boys leave tonight. Don't come back.
你们今晚就走 不要回来
I don't want to see you again. Understood?
我不想再见到你们 明白吗?
Well, that was a complete waste of time.
哎 这完全就是浪费时间
Not one security camera near SAC Federal caught the robbery.
萨克拉门托联邦银行附近没有一个监控捕捉到劫案的画面
Thanks.
谢了
Sure. What's all this?
不客气 这都是什么?
Case files and footage from the other robberies.
案件资料和其他几起劫案拍到的画面
Check this out.
看看这个
The SAC Fed job was by far the largest haul...
萨克拉门托联邦银行是目前最大的目标...
more than double any of the other robberies.
现金额度是其他劫案的两倍多
- They're getting ambitious.  - Not they.
- 这些人开始野心勃勃了  - 不是这些人
He. Now in each one of the robberies, there's maybe
只是一个人 在每个劫案里 摄像头被涂黑之前
30 seconds of footage before the cameras were blacked out.
总有30秒左右的图像
That was enough to analyze
这就足够拿来分析
the suspects' height, weight, build, and skin color, so I did.
疑犯的身高 体重 体形和肤色 我试了一下
And guess what.
猜猜怎么着
Only one of the robbers was involved in all four crimes.
4次劫案里只有一个劫匪是吻合的
That's him.
就是他
So the other robbers... they were work for hire?
这么说来其他的劫匪... 都是临时雇来的?
Exactly. They do one job and then they disappear.
正是如此 他们做完一次就消失
But if we can find this guy,
但如果我们能找到这个主谋
we find them all. He's the key.
就能一网打尽了 他就是关键
Do you remember anything about the men who did this?
你记得劫匪的样子吗?
No. Not a thing.
不 一点都不记得
You know Ernie and I were up for the same promotion?
你们应该知道我和Ernie当时都在争取同一个升职机会?
I was mad when I didn't get it.
当我失败的时候 我快疯了
But not now.
但现在我不这么想了
That could've been me in there.
不然那里面死的人就是我了
Ernie was a good man.
Ernie是个好人
He didn't deserve this.
他不该这么英年早逝
What were you doing during the robbery?
劫案发生时你在做什么?
What they told me to.
照他们要求趴着
I am not trying to get shot over this job.
我可不想为了这份工作就把命丢了
Ernie must've done something wrong. Poor fool.
Ernie肯定做错了什么事 真是可怜的傻瓜
And that's when the robbers ordered you to the ground?
就是劫匪命令你们趴在地上的时候?
Yeah. He stuck a gun right in my face.
是的 他拿着把枪直指着我的脸
I was gonna grab it and take those guys down,
我本想拔枪 然后放倒他们
but I just had back surgery,
可惜我背上刚好有伤
so I didn't want to risk the loss of innocent lives.
所以我不能冒险伤害到无辜的生命
After that, one of the robbers
之后 其中一个劫匪
took assistant manager Ernie Wright into the vault.
就把副经理Ernie Wright带到了金库里面
I think so. I don't really know. I was in the back.
应该是的 我不太清楚 我当时在后面
During the robbery?
劫案发生的时候?
In the men's room.
我当时在厕所里
Is this really necessary?
这也有必要说吗?
I've already been through...
我已经做过...
You were in the men's room the whole time?
整个抢劫过程 你都是在厕所吗?
Yes.
是
I was, uh, washing up when I heard the gunshot.
我当时正在洗脸 突然听见一声枪响
Of course, I didn't know it was a gunshot at the time.
当然 我一开始不知道是枪声
It wasn't until I stepped into the hall
直到我走到大厅 听到一声尖叫
that I heard the screaming.
我才意识到的
Was anyone back there with you?
厕所那里就你一个人吗?
Not that I saw.
我没看到
Ernie and I had lunch plans.
Ernie和我本来准备去吃午饭
We were just about to leave
我们正准备离开的
when I went into the back to use the restroom.
但是我突然想去厕所 就到后面去了
Yes, we saw as much on the security footage.
是的 我们在保安录像里看到了
We also saw your manager, Armin Gagnon,
我们还看到你们经理 Armin Gagnon
heading into the men's room just behind you.
在你后面进了男厕所
Do you remember seeing him?
你看到过他吗?
No.
没有
Not until after I heard the shot.
我听见枪声以后看到了
I opened the door, and Armin was standing there.
听见枪声我打开门 看到Armin就站在那
Then I heard the robbers shouting, so I closed the door,
然后我听见劫匪在喊叫 所以我把门给关上了
and I... I hid in the stall until they left.
然后... 然后我就躲在里面直到他们跑了
Mr.Gagnon was in the hallway?
Gagnon先生站在走廊里?
Here?
这儿?
Yes.
是的
Why?
怎么了?
Just trying to get the facts straight, ma'am.
只是想弄清到底发生什么了
Was Ernie the type to fight back?
Ernie是那种见义勇为的人吗?
No.
不是
Ernie was a big Teddy bear.
Ernie就像大一点的泰迪熊
He'd never fight unless it was to protect someone he loved.
我想 他要不是为了保护所爱的人 一定不会去和劫匪争斗的
Hey. How's it going?
嘿 进展如何?
I think I got it.
我想我有线索了
Okay. Lay it on me.
好吧 和我说说
This ringleader...
这个主谋...
he had to have planned the robberies, right?
他是计划所有抢劫案的人 对吧?
Right.
没错
Which means he probably visited each of the banks
这就意味着他可能在抢劫之前
before he robbed them.
就去过银行调查过
On camera and without a mask, yeah.
可能会被摄像头拍下来
So we run all the security footage
所以我们把这几家银行的
through facial recognition software, and when we find
保安录像做一遍脸部比对 可能会找到
the man that visited all four banks before the robberies,
在四家银行被抢劫前都出现过的人
we find our ringleader.
那人就是主谋了
Great idea.
绝妙的方法
It's an idea. I don't know if I'd call it great.
是个方法 但是不能说很绝妙
Ah, he's just jealous.
别理他 他嫉妒而已
What are you wearing?
你穿的是什么?
Oh, these things?
这双鞋吗?
Ah, they're loaners.
只是替代品
How about this?
这样如何?
Whoever figures out the bank robber's name first
谁先找到那个银行抢劫犯的名字
wins lunch for a week.
谁就请客吃一个星期午饭
Yeah, that usually doesn't end well for us.
每次一打赌 结局可能就不会很好
What do you say, Grace? You feeling lucky?
你接受吗 Grace? 觉得会赢吗?
You're on.
没问题
萨克拉门托联邦银行
It was closed.
是关着的
You're certain?
你确定?
Must've been closed.
肯定是锁着的
The safe deposit vault is always closed.
保险库的门一直锁着的
I think it was closed.
我认为是关上的
Yeah.
是
I want you to close your eyes.
我想让你闭上眼睛
Hey, we're grown-ups. Come on.
喂 我们都是成人了 快点
Now put your mental self back in this very spot,
现在 将自我意识聚焦在这里
in that very moment.
在那个时候
I want you to hear the sound that your shoes made
我想让你回忆起来你走过这里时
on this marble floor.
鞋子擦碰地板的声音
Now without opening your eyes,
别睁开眼睛
I want you to picture the door as you pass by.
我想让你回忆经过这扇门时的情形
Can you do that?
能记起来吗?
Can you see the door?
看见门了吗?
Yes.
看见了
And?
然后呢?
It was open.
是开着的
A-ha.
没错
Which means someone
这就意味着
went inside the safe deposit vault during the robbery.
有人在抢劫过程中进过这个保险库
Mostly likely a robber
很可能是劫匪
trying to take something from a deposit box.
想从保险库里抢点什么
Oh, my. What if they did?
天啊 他们真的抢了?
Let's find out, shall we?
我们去看看吧 好吗?
That's impossible.
这不太可能
It is?
为什么?
The safe deposit boxes are legal property
这保险库里的东西是
of the individuals who rent them.
是租借人的合法财产
We don't even have keys. Only the owners do.
连我们都开不了 只有保险库所有者才有钥匙
Only the owners do.
保险库所有者才有钥匙
You wouldn't happen to have
你有那些租借人的
a list of those names, would you?
名单 对吧?
We got a match.
找到了
Oh, good morning to you, too.
哦 早上好
The suspect visited Pacific Bank of Modesto
嫌犯在抢劫的一个星期前分别
and Fresno Savings and Loan a week before each was robbed.
去过莫德斯托太平洋银行和弗雷斯诺储蓄银行
He comes in, cases the place, then leaves,
他进去 查探了一下 然后走了
without making a transaction. I think we found our guy.
也没进行过交易 我想他就是我们要找的人
His name anyway.
弄清他的名字了
Well, congratulations.
恭喜你们
Me, too.
我也弄清了
You did? When?
你弄清了? 什么时候?
When did you figure it out?
你是什么时候查到的?
About an hour ago.
一个小时以前
Ah, well, there you have it.
你就这水平了
I figured it out two hours ago,
我两小时前就想出来了
so it looks like I win the bet.
看来我这赌是我赢了
Okay, what's his name?
好吧 他叫什么?
Oh, I'm not gonna fall
噢 我才不会上
for that old trick, Grace.
这种当呢 Grace
Write it down on a piece of paper
先在纸上把名字写下来
so I know that you're not lying.
我就能知道你是不是在撒谎了
John Hutten.
他叫John Hutten
How did you do that?
你怎么做到的?
How did I do it? Does it matter? I did it.
我怎么做到的? 这有什么关系? 反正我赢了
Rigsby, we got a work address on the suspect. Let's go.
Rigsby 找到嫌犯的工作地点了 我们走
Uh, yeah.
呃 好吧
Uh, by the way, Grace,
话说回来 Grace
there's a fabulous Thai place on Sixth Street.
第六大街上有家很棒的泰餐馆
They make a delicious Tom Kha Gai.
他们做的泰式香浓椰奶鸡汤非常不错
Ooh. Can't wait.
等不及尝尝了
Stockton货运公司
Mr. Hutten?
Hutten先生?
John Hutten?
你是John Hutten吗?
Put it down. Let me see your hands.
把东西放下 把手举起来
I'm Agent Lisbon with the CBI.
我是加州调查局的Lisbon探员
Just want to ask you a few questions.
想问你几个问题
Agent Lisbon, you said?
你说你是Lisbon探员?
Pleasure to meet you.
很高兴认识你
John William Hutten.
John William Hutten先生
You were arrested twice for grand theft auto.
你由于偷盗车辆被逮捕两次
You served 18 months in Folsom.
你在Folsom监狱监禁了18个月
Here you are,
你又来了一次
a suspect in a robbery and homicide.
这次是涉嫌抢劫和凶杀
Is there a charge at the end of this, Detective?
讯问过后你会起诉我吗 探员?
Where were you yesterday at noon?
你昨天中午在哪儿?
Home. Sick.
在家 我病了
Is there anyone who can verify that?
有人能证明吗?
No, because I was home, sick.
没有 因为我病了 在家休息
You were caught on camera
中央谷有四家银行的
at four banks in the Central Valley.
监控录像都拍到了你
All four of those banks were robbed
在这之后的一个星期里
within weeks of you visiting.
这四家银行都被抢劫了
Which is conclusive evidence of what?
这能得出什么结论?
I think it's evidence that your client
我觉得这是你的委托人
planned to commit armed robbery.
参与持枪抢劫的证据
Then charge him, and we'll see what a jury has to say.
那就起诉他吧 看看陪审团是什么态度
What were you doing in those banks?
你去拿些银行干什么?
Times are tight.
最近手头紧
I was shopping for competitive interest rates
我在找一家贷款利率
in money market accounts.
划算一点的银行
And you've been smart so far.
你一直很精明
Blacking out security cameras, going straight for the vault.
每次都会涂黑监控探头 直接去金库
But this time, you screwed up, and somebody ended up dead.
但这次你搞砸了 有人死了
Maybe the SAC Fed job was too big for you.
也许萨克拉门托联邦银行的这次抢劫太大了
O... or maybe the murder was a part of the plan all along.
或者... 也许谋杀本来就是计划里的一环
I didn't rob Sacramento Federal.
我没有抢劫萨克拉门托联邦银行
I didn't rob any bank.
一家都没抢
But if I did, I certainly wouldn't need to kill someone.
但如果我要抢 肯定就不会杀人
That's just sloppy.
这太草率了
Now I've had my brushes with the law,
法律的确让我吃过亏
but I've learned some things from them,
但我也学到了东西
like the fact that you can't use my past against me in court
比如说 在法庭上 你不能用我的过去来当证据
and no matter what you say inside this little room,
还有 你在这个小房间里无论讲了什么
you have nothing on me.
都是没证据的
So unless there's something else, Agent Lisbon,
所以如果没别的问题了 Lisbon探员
I think I should be getting back to work.
我想我该回去工作了
We'll see ourselves out.
我们自己出去
Hello.
你好
Patrick Jane. I'm working the robbery/murder case.
我叫Patrick Jane 正在调查那个抢劫谋杀案
We already spoke with Agent Lisbon.
我们已经跟Lisbon探员谈过了
Yes, I know. I saw the whole thing.
当然 我知道 都看到了
Uh, just a head's-up, for future reference,
呃 我就提一句 提醒一下你
that large mirror is, in fact, a window.
那面大镜子 其实是个窗户
What do you want?
你想说什么?
Uh, I can see that you're a professional,
呃 我知道你是专业的
but, uh, Agent Lisbon was correct. Uh,
但Lisbon探员说得没错
this last robbery was a break in pattern.
最近这起抢劫和以往的不同
Uh, I don't mean that just because someone was killed.
我并不是指有人在这起抢劫中死了
I'm talking about the entire job.
我是在说整个过程
How's that?
怎么不同了?
Well, the other three robberies were simple...
其他三起抢劫都很简单...
small town banks, very little security,
小镇银行 很少的安保人员
straightforward.
一击必中
But SAC Federal... bigger.
但萨克拉门托联邦银行... 比较大
Much bigger.
打多了
Mr. Jane, we've already answered...
Jane先生 我们已经回答了...
Now there had to be something
一定有些契机
that gave you that extra bit of confidence
让你有这样的自信
to pull this one off.
完成这起抢劫
What was that?
是什么呢?
John, don't say a word.
John 什么都别说
You had an inside man.
你有个内应
Yes.
没错
Of course.
正是如此
I should've known.
我早该猜到了
I used to use one on occasion in my stage act.
我以前舞台表演的时候也这么干过
- Stage act, huh?  - Mm.
- 舞台表演吗?  - 没错
Uh, let me guess... balloon sculpting?
呃 让我猜猜... 是表演扭气球吗?
Animal impressions?
弄成动物的形状?
That's it.
够了
John's a good worker.
John是个很好的工人
Shows up on time, keeps his mouth shut.
上班准时 不嚼舌根
Does he hang out with any of his coworkers?
他和其他工人一起出去玩吗?
Not that I've noticed. Keeps to himself mostly.
我没看到过 大部分时间他都自己呆着
Has he been acting strange recently?
他最近有什么奇怪的举动吗?
Do anything out of the ordinary?
有没有做什么不寻常的事情?
Like come in in a dress?
比如穿个裙子来上班?
No. Nothing like that.
不 没有这种事
Can you confirm
你能不能确定
whether or not Hutten was at work on these dates?
在这几天Hutten有没有来上班?
I can't help you.
帮不了你们
These are all before John started working here.
这些日期都是John来这工作之前的
The last few days... Hutten called in sick?
前几天... 他打电话请病假了?
Yeah, he said he had some kind of bug. Couldn't get out of bed.
是的 他说他抱恙在身 无法下床
Do you believe him?
你信吗?
Sure. Why wouldn't I? It's been going around.
当然了 我为啥不信 这病都蔓延了
What do you mean by that?
你这么说什么意思?
Two of my other guys got the same thing.
还有两名员工也是这种情况
Arroyo brothers...
Arroyo兄弟俩...
Jorge, Cesar.
Jorge 还有Cesar
We're gonna need their home address.
我们需要这些人的住址
When are you getting your shoes back?
你什么时候能把自己鞋子取回来?
They're not so bad, are they?
这鞋子也不差啊 是吧?
Are you sure this is the right place to do this?
你确定这种场合合适吗?
Well, Hutten's inside man works at the bank,
呃 Hutten的内应就在银行工作
and it seems...
而且貌似...
Everyone that works at the bank is here. I'll be right back.
银行里的人今天都到齐了 我去去就来
Jane, wait.
Jane 等等
W...
你...
Hello.
你好
Were you friends with my grandson?
你是我孙子的朋友吗?
Perfect. Glad you're all here.
太好了 你们都在这
Quick. What's your favorite color?
快说 你最喜欢什么颜色?
- What?  - Favorite color. Red? Green? Blue?
- 啥?  - 你最喜欢的颜色是红色? 绿色? 还是蓝色?
Blue.
蓝色
Out of all your employees, which is the least trustworthy?
在你所有的员工里 哪个是最不可信的?
What? None of them.
胡说啥? 没人不可信
You. What's your name?
还有你 你叫什么名字?
Casey.
我叫Casey
Casey, you work in banking,
Casey 你从事银行业
yet your personal finances are a wreck.
自己的个人财务却一塌糊涂
No, they're not.
不 没有的事
Oh, please. That handbag on your salary? Dead giveaway.
拜托 你工资买得起这个包? 它彻底出卖了你
And you bite your nails. Sure sign of anxiety.
你还咬指甲 这是焦虑的表现
Yet someone as anxious as you
不过你这么焦虑的人
probably doesn't have the stomach
可能也没勇气
to pull off a crime like this.
实施这种罪行
Crime? What crime?
罪行? 什么罪?
You didn't like Ernie, did you?
你不喜欢Ernie 对吧?
You felt threatened by him.
你觉得被他威胁了
Who told you that?
谁告诉你的?
You did just now.
你刚刚表现出来的
Clearly not smart enough to pull off a robbery.
你显然也没聪明到能去抢劫
What'd you say to me?
你在胡说啥呢?
You heard me. Uh, when I asked
你都听到了 我问你们经理
you manager who he trusted the least,
他最不信任谁的时候
his eyes darted to you.
他就瞟了你一眼
- They did not.  - Repeat after me...
- 我没有  - 跟着我重复一遍...
"I am the inside man."
"我是内应"
Hell, no.
我才不会说呢
Just as I thought. Not you either.
跟我想的一样 你也不是内应
Wait. Th... there was an inside man?
等等 有... 有内应?
- What's your name?  - Uh, Tai.
- 你叫什么?  - 我叫Tai
Tai. Pleasure to meet you.
Tai 很高兴认识你
Have we met? Did you help rob Sacramento Federal Bank?
我们见过吗? 你是不是打劫萨克拉门托联邦银行的帮凶?
No.
不是
- You sure?  - Yeah.
- 你确定?  - 当然了
- Yes?  - No.
- 真的不是?  - 不是
- No? Yes?  - Get off me.
- 不是? 是?  - 放开我
This... this is completely inappropriate.
这... 你这样实在是太过分了吧
Show Ernie some respect.
拜托尊重一下Ernie
Yes. Ernie.
好吧 Ernie呀
Absolutely right.
说的对
My apologies.
我道歉
That was 1982?
这是1982拍的?
Yeah.
是呀
Jane. Jane, where you going?
Jane 嘿 你要去哪?
I just have to check on something. I'll be right back.
我要去核实些事情 很快回来
- No.  - You know, you should probably answer that.
- 不行  - 你应该先接电话吧
It's very important.
肯定是重要电话
Damn it, Jane.
该死 Jane
- Hello?  - Hey, boss.
- 喂?  - 嘿 头儿
We checked out the Arroyo brothers' apartment.
我们查到了Arroyo兄弟俩的公寓
Place is empty.
人去楼空了
According to the building manager,
据大厦管理员说
they took off late last night.
他们昨晚连夜动身的
Any word on where they were going?
知道他们去哪了吗?
No forwarding address,
没有确切地址
but they told the manager
不过他们告诉管理员
they were headed to Mexico to visit family.
他们要去墨西哥探亲
And we also tracked down the van that was used in the robbery.
我们还追踪到了劫案中使用的那辆卡车
It was torched pretty bad.
销毁得非常彻底了
Yeah, it doesn't look like we're gonna get anything form it.
看起来我们无法从中得到什么线索了
All right.
好吧
Flag the Arroyo brothers with customs.
让海关拦截Arroyo兄弟俩
If they're on their way to Mexico,
如果他们在去墨西哥的路上
maybe we can get them before they cross the border.
我们可能会在他们过境之前抓到他们
All right.
好的
Uh, Lisbon.
过来 Lisbon
Found something.
找到点线索
You will never believe who was working with the bank robbers.
你绝对不敢相信谁是和劫匪合作的那个人
Ernie Wright.
就是Ernie Wright
Probably shouldn't discuss it here.
也许我们不该在这讨论这事
We're very sorry for your loss.
我们对您的遭遇非常遗憾
There's no way Ernie could do something like this.
Ernie绝不可能做出这种事情来
There's just no way.
不可能的
We found a one-way ticket to Brazil in Ernie's name.
我们找到一张去巴西的单程票 写着Ernie的名字
No.
不
No. That's absurd.
太荒谬了
Ernie?
你说Ernie?
Robbing a bank? I mean, he wasn't the type.
他会抢银行? 得了吧 他不是这种人
He was exactly the type.
他就是这种人
Judging from these photographs here,
从这里的照片来看
I'd say Ernie became a different man.
我只能说Ernie像变了个人似的
Yeah, he lost weight,
是呀 他减肥了
started dressing sharper.
穿着也注意了很多
Powerful external transformations
外型上变得强壮
can often coincide with even larger internal ones.
往往符合他内心的更大的变化
He was trying to better himself.
他只是想提升他自己
Why? Because of you?
为什么? 因为你吗?
I encouraged him, of course.
当然 我也鼓励了他
I loved him.
我爱他
Ernie was just a teller when we met.
我们认识的时候Ernie只是个出纳员
He was still living at home.
还住在父母家
Shy, inexperienced with women?
对待女人既羞涩又毫无经验?
Yes.
是的
And what changed?
有什么发生了变化?
He finished his degree,
他拿到了学位
got promoted to assistant manager,
升职成了副经理
and bought this house.
还买了这个房子
And you were by his side every step of the way.
这一路以来你都在他身边
You must have seen something very special in Ernie.
你可能看到了Ernie身上不同寻常的一面
Yes.
是的
I saw that he was sweet
我发现他非常贴心
and how good a man he was.
也是个非常好的男人
He could never do something like this.
他绝不可能做出这种事
No way.
不可能的
Where'd you grow up?
你在哪长大的?
Upstate New York.
纽约北部
A town called Newburgh.
一个叫Newburgh的镇子
Hmm. And you two?
嗯 那你们两个呢?
Uh, Chicago.
我在芝加哥长大
Here.
萨克拉门托
In Sacramento. Why?
我就在这长大 怎么了?
No reason.
没理由
So if we prove Hutten's connection to Ernie,
如果我们证明Hutten和Ernie有联系
we prove Hutten's guilt.
就定Hutten的罪
But a connection should've come up by now.
不过至今还没找到他们的联系
How did Hutten know Ernie?
Hutten是怎么认识Ernie的?
- Hot reading.  - What?
- 热读术  - 什么?
Well, Hutten's a careful, meticulous professional.
Hutten是个非常谨慎小心翼翼的行家
He wouldn't have used an inside man
他不可能用一个
that could be traced back to him,
会追踪到他身上的内应
so he researched the staff at the bank.
所以他事先调查了银行里的所有职员
Hot reading. Very easy to do these days.
热读术(事先对他人进行身份调查) 很简单的方法
And he kept digging until he found someone with shaky ethics
他一直在挖掘资料直到他找到了一个道德感不坚定
and a yen for a better life... Ernie.
又非常想要更好生活的人... 就是Ernie
Hmm.
有道理
Wow. It's late.
哇 这么晚了
What are you still doing here?
你还在这做什么?
Trying to find a connection between Hutten and Ernie Wright.
想找到Hutten和Ernie Wright之间的联系
I've checked Ernie's e-mail account,
我查了Ernie的邮箱账户
text messages, and cell phone records.
短信息和通话记录
Nothing. So far there's no sign of communication between them.
没发现 至今还没有任何迹象表明他俩有联系
Mm. Sorry to hear it.
嗯 真遗憾
Oh, listen, uh, the bank manager's supposed to send out
对了 嘿 经理应该会发一份
a list of safety deposit box owners.
保险箱用户的名单过来
Right. It's on my desk.
是的 就在我桌子上呢
Thank you very much.
非常感谢
Silly me. Almost forgot.
看我笨的 差点忘了
I've really been craving Italian lately,
我最近特别喜欢意大利风情
so what do you say we get a nice linguine
不如我们明天中午的午餐
for lunch tomorrow?
吃美味的意大利扁面条怎么样?
Huh?
怎么样?
Yeah. Okay.
嗯 好吧
Ciao. Ciao.
说定了噢 拜拜
Jane.
嘿 Jane
Jane, wake up.
Jane 醒醒
Yeah. What's the time?
哎呦 几点了?
8:00.
8点了
Oh, we have to get going.
我们要出发了
Where?
去哪?
I'll explain it all in the car.
上车再跟你解释
No. You'll explain it now, please.
不行 现在就解释吧
Oh, I like it when you get all authoritarian on me.
我就喜欢你拿权利来压我
Talk. Where are we going?
说吧 我们要去哪?
To catch Ernie's killer.
去抓杀死Ernie的凶手啊
How? We don't have anything on Hutten.
怎么抓? 我们还没任何证据逮捕Hutten呢
Hutten didn't kill Ernie.
Hutten没有谋杀Ernie
He didn't?
不是他?
Well, he robbed the bank, all right,
好吧 他确实抢劫了银行
but he was telling the truth
但是他说他没有开枪杀死任何人
when he said he didn't need to shoot anyone.
这句的确是真话
Why would he do that? It's sloppy, not his style.
他为什么要这么做? 这行为很草率 不是他的行事作风
Jane, I need more than that.
Jane 继续说
You remember the safe deposit vault
你记得不 抢劫的时候保险箱寄存库的
was open during the robbery?
库门是开着的?
I just assumed that someone took something from there,
我一开始假设有人从那里拿走了什么东西
but, uh, I got it all backwards.
不过 我回想了一下
They didn't take anything.
他们并不是去拿东西的
They put something in there.
而是往里面藏了什么东西
What?
什么东西?
You really want me to tell you?
你真的想让我告诉你?
It's gonna ruin the surprise.
这就没什么惊喜了嘛
Yes. I don't like surprises.
没错 我就是不喜欢惊喜
Three guesses then.
那就猜三次
I'll give you a hint.
我会给你提示
It's... it's not animal
那个... 不是动物
or vegetable.
也不是蔬菜
You know, we can't open a safe deposit box without a warrant.
要知道 没有搜查令 我们就不能打开银行的保管箱
We can if we have the owner's permission.
如果有了行长的同意就可以
Uh, we don't open for a half-hour.
呃 我们半小时后开始营业
Is everything all right?
有什么问题吗?
Everything's fine.
没问题
We just want to ask your employees some questions.
我们只是想问你的下属一些问题
It shouldn't take long.
不会花很久的
Can you have everyone who was here at the time of the robbery
你能让抢劫发生时正在工作的所有职员
gather in the safe deposit vault,
在保险金库里集中吗?
yourself included?
当然也包括你
Yes, absolutely.
好的 当然没问题
Has there been a break in the case?
案件有突破了吗?
You'll see.
马上告诉你
What's this all about?
这是要做什么?
Oh, I've gathered you here to help catch Ernie's killer.
我让你们在这里集中 是为了抓杀Ernie的凶手
How are we gonna catch the bank robber?
我们怎么可能抓到抢匪?
Well, the bank robber didn't kill Ernie.
抢匪并没有啥Ernie
Then who did?
那是谁杀的?
Uh, one of you.
呃 你们中的一个人
- What?  - I don't think so, buddy.
- 什么?  - 我可不这么认为 兄弟
I would never ever hurt Ernie.
我才不会伤害Ernie
Whoa. There's no need for objections.
急于反驳是没有用的
One of you shot Ernie during the robbery,
你们中有一个人在抢劫发生时开枪杀了Ernie
and you hid the gun in a safe deposit box.
并把枪藏在了保险柜里
- I am sure of it.  - But that...
- 我很确定  - 但这...
Yes, exactly, Doug. That means the killer would've
确实如此 Doug 这就意味着凶手
had to have planned the murder a long way in advance,
很早之前就已经计划了这次谋杀
so one of you, who I will identify shortly,
我一会儿就能指认 你们中
is a cold-blooded schemer.
有个冷血阴谋家
Now first of all,
首先
if there's anyone here that feels the urge to leave,
如果有人非常想离开这里
feel free. Please do so. But know this...
请便 可以马上离开 但要知道...
we will assume you are our killer.
我们会认为你就是要找的凶手
Armin, if you wouldn't mind unlocking the vault door.
Armin 请打开金库的门
Thank you.
谢谢
Before we begin,
在我们开始前
uh, Agent Lisbon has a few words.
Lisbon探员有话要说
Agent Lisbon?
Lisbon探员?
I've been authorized by the district attorney's office
检察官办公室直接授权我
to offer Ernie's killer a plea deal.
给杀Ernie的凶手一个口头协议
Ten years in prison
如果你现在合作
if you cooperate now and open the deposit box.
并打开保险箱 刑期十年
Ten years.
十年
That's a very generous offer.
真是个不错的协议
And all you have to do
你只需要在我之前
is open the box before I'm forced to.
打开保险箱就可以
Just as I'd hoped.
就跟我想的一样
Here.
这里
Definitely somewhere here.
肯定在这个区域里
You sure?
你确定吗?
Positive.
确定
The offer is now 15 years.
现在的协议是15年
All right, this is absurd.
得了吧 这太荒唐了
You can't play some game with people's lives.
你们不能用游戏来决定人的命运
Armin, we're the law. We can do whatever we want.
Armin 我们代表法律 当然可以为所欲为
Any takers for 15 years?
有人要认罪吗?
Very well.
很好
Not really feeling it.
这里没什么感觉
Yes.
对了
It's somewhere in this group here.
就是在这块里
The offer is now 20 years.
现在的协议是20年
20 years right now. There it is.
现在认罪就是20年 这就是你
Your last chance of seeing freedom in your lifetime.
如果你想在有生之年重获自由 这是你最后的机会
All you need is a little key that fits in a little lock.
你要做的 就是那出和这个保险箱匹配的小钥匙
Suit yourselves.
那就随你便
I believe...
我绝对...
it's one of these three here.
就是这三个里的一个
Starting on five. Starting on five.
5字开头的 5字开头的
Uh, Stephens,
呃 一个叫Stephens
Hudson,
一个叫Hudson
Keene.
一个叫Keene
Stephens.
这个是Stephens
Hudson. Keene.
Hudson还有Keene
25 years.
25年
If we have to force open the box, the deal's off.
如果我们要强行打开保险箱 就没有协议了
You'll be facing first-degree murder,
你将面对一级谋杀指控
and the district attorney
区检查官也会
will aggressively pursue the death penalty.
向培生图案强烈建议死刑
You might get life if you're lucky.
如果幸运的话 你能活下来
All right, Jane. Which one is it?
好吧 Jane 是哪个?
Yeah. Yeah. Uh, Stephens...
好的 呃 Stephens...
No. No.
不 不是这个
Keene?
Keene吗?
No, I don't think so.
不对 不像这个
Perhaps it's Hudson.
也许是Hudson这个
Wait.
等等
Nancy?
Nancy 是你?
I knew it.
我就知道
Oh, my God. You evil bitch!
天呐 你这个毒妇!
Oh, there's no need for that. Let's see if the key fits.
噢 不用这么装腔作势 我们看看钥匙对不对
Shall we?
好吗?
Nancy Sterling, you're under arrest
Nancy Sterling 你由于涉嫌
for the murder of Ernie Wright.
谋杀Ernie Wright被捕
Turn around. Put your hands behind your back.
转过身去 双手放在背后
When I met Ernie, he was a loser...
我遇到Ernie的时候 他就是个废物...
fat, stuck in his job, still living with his parents.
很胖 只会埋头工作 还跟父母住在一起
And you helped him change?
你帮他做了改变?
Helped him?
帮他?
I made him the man he was.
是我造就了现在的他
I supported him when he went back to school,
他要回学校念书 是我赞助了他
found him his house,
帮他找房子
I even helped him get promoted.
甚至帮他升了职
And how did he repay me?
他怎么回报我的?
He completely lost interest in me.
他对我根本就不感兴趣了
And you resented him for it.
而你就因此恨上了他
You're damn right I did.
我恨死他了
I thought he was cheating on me.
我觉得他出轨了
He was getting in shape,
他开始注意形象
working out.
经常锻炼
Don't think I didn't notice other women looking at him.
他以为我不知道别的女人都盯着他看
You should've seen Ernie.
你该看看Ernie的样子
He loved it.
他就喜欢这样
Is that when you began spying on him?
你就是因为这个开始查看他的隐私的吗?
I checked his phone, his e-mail.
我看了他的电话 他的邮件
One time I followed him into one of those Internet cafes.
有一次我跟着他去了一个网吧
So shady.
太可疑了
He was using a secret e-mail account.
他用了一个秘密邮箱账号
Which you hacked into.
你也进去看过了
That's when I found the e-mails.
我就是那个时候发现的这些邮件
And you're referring to the correspondence
你指的是Ernie和John Hutten
between Ernie and John Hutten, right?
之间的通信 对吧?
More like step-by-step details
更像是一个
outlining how they were gonna rob the bank.
如何抢银行的详细计划
I didn't know what to do.
我不知道该怎么做
But then I found that ticket to Brazil.
但之后我找到了那张去巴西的机票
Ernie was gonna leave me...
Ernie想要离开我...
me, after everything I'd done for him.
我为他都付出了这么多
I don't think so.
我才不会同意
I had the details for the robbery.
我有抢劫的详细计划
I knew exactly where everyone was going to be
我很清楚他们的位置
and when they were going to be there.
以及什么时候会到
So I hid.
所以我躲了起来
And I waited for the robbers to leave.
等着抢匪们离开
- Five, six...  - Then went into the cash vault.
- 五 六...  - 然后去现金金库
Ernie never suspected a thing.
Ernie毫无防备
I'm keeping the ring.
戒指就不还你了
What are you...
你在...
You should've seen the look on his face.
你真该看看他的表情
It was perfect,
一切都很完美
except for one thing.
除了一件事
I left the safe deposit door open.
我忘了关金库的门
When I tried to go back and close it,
当时我想回去关上它
it was too late.
但已经晚了
You know, you could've just called the police,
要知道 你本可以打电话报警
turned Ernie in.
告发Ernie的
I thought about that.
我也这么想过
I really did.
真的想过
But Ernie was gonna leave me.
但Ernie想抛弃我
Me.
抛弃我
I was planning our wedding,
我在准备我们的婚礼
and he was just gonna disappear forever.
而他却想永远消失
Unh-unh.
想都别想
He deserved everything he got.
他是罪有应得
This is getting to be grounds for harassment, Agent Lisbon.
这已经可以算是骚扰了 Lisbon探员
I told him this wouldn't take long.
我告诉过他 不会很久的
"I will arrive Tuesday at 12:00 p.m. exactly.
"我会在周二正午到达
You will be in the lobby.
你在大厅等我
I will take you in back at gunpoint,
我会拿枪指着你 带你到后面
where you will open the vault.
你帮我们打开金库
You will help load the cash into duffel bags,
你把钱装进行李袋
then you will stay behind."
然后原地待着"
Ernie's fiancee was spying on him.
Ernie的未婚妻在暗中监视他
Text messages, phone calls.
短信 电话 都在监视
She even found the secret e-mail account that he was using.
她甚至找到了他在用的秘密邮箱
As a matter of fact, she saved every e-mail you sent him.
事实上 她存了所有的邮件
You ready to talk about that deal now?
你现在想认罪了吗?
Hutten wasn't the killer,
Hutten不是凶手
so it had to be somebody else in the bank,
所以肯定是银行里的人干的
but why Nancy?
但为什么怀疑Nancy?
Whoever killed Ernie
杀了Ernie的人
had to have known about the robbery in advance.
肯定事先就知道抢劫的事
Well, Nancy was, uh, the likely candidate.
Nancy知道的几率 呃 就很大
She's also a classic power dater.
她也是典型的主宰型恋人
A what?
什么恋人?
Oh, you know the type.
噢 你知道的
They date down so they have all the power in a relationship.
他们总会找比自己差的谈恋爱 掌控一切
Oh. And how did you know this?
噢 你怎么知道的?
Uh, well, she had more than half of the space in Ernie's closet.
呃 她的衣服占了Ernie衣柜的二分之一以上
I mean, she didn't even live there
我是说 她都不在哪儿住
and she had more than half of his closet space?
怎么会需要二分之一以上的衣柜空间呢?
And how did you know which safe deposit box was Nancy's?
你怎么知道哪个保险柜是Nancy的?
I hot read her.
热读术
I had the list of owners and the bank staff files.
我有行长和所有银行职员的档案
I knew one of the names had to be Nancy in disguise.
我知道有个名字一定是Nancy用的假名
Hudson?
就是Hudson?
Mm.
没错
No one ever strays very far when it comes to false names.
没人会想一个完全无关的假名
Nancy said that she grew up
Nancy说她在纽约的
in a small town in upstate New York... Newburgh.
一个叫做Newburgh的小镇长大
On the Hudson River.
就在Hudson河畔
On the Hudson River. Mm.
没错 就在Hudson河畔
You know, these shoes are actually quite comfortable.
要知道 这鞋真的非常舒服
They're growing on me.
我都穿惯了
Not on me.
我可不习惯
No?
不习惯吗?
Oh, hey, Teresa. Glad you made it.
嘿 Teresa 很高兴你赶过来了
It's a pretty high-class crowd. I wish you would've warned me.
大家都位高权重 你该提醒我的
Nah. They're pussycats. Come on. I'll introduce you.
他们才没这么可怕 来吧 我介绍你们认识
Teresa Lisbon, this is district attorney Don Wolcott.
这位是Teresa Lisbon 这位是Don Wolcott检察长
Hi.
你好
FBI Bureau Director Charles Bailey...
联邦调查局局长Charles Bailey...
Sir.
你好
- Senator Eileen Dawkins.  - State Senator.
- Eileen Dawkins议员  - 是州医院
Here. Have a seat. Get you a drink?
来吧 请坐 要杯喝的吗?
Yeah. Can I have a scotch on the rocks, please?
好的 请各位一杯苏格兰威士忌加冰 可以吗?
You got it.
马上送到
Oh, I think you know this guy, right?
我想你已经认识这位了 对吧?
Teresa.
是Teresa啊
I didn't take you for a gambler.
我以为你不赌博呢
Oh, it's not gambling if you know you're gonna win.
噢 如果知道一定会赢就不算赌博了
Well, we got a live one. Watch out.
这位可是蓄势待发啊 大家小心了
There you go.
给你酒
Thank you. Thank you.
谢谢 谢谢
Look at that, huh?
看看这个
Beautiful work.
真不错
Yeah. Thank you.
太好了 谢谢
Okay.
好吧
Here.
来
There we go.
给你钱
For the rental.
这是借鞋子的钱
Thank you. Good night, Mr. Jane. Good night.
谢谢 晚安 Jane先生 晚安
Good night, Niko.
Niko 晚安
I'm headed home. I'll see you tomorrow.
我要回家了 明天见
Uh, yeah, tomorrow... curry, definitely.
呃 对了 明天... 吃咖喱吧
I feel like some Indian.
我想吃印度菜了
You gotta tell me. How did you come up with Hutten's name?
你得告诉我 你是怎么知道Hutten名字的?
It's driving me crazy.
我快疯了
Fair enough.
好吧
Get a pen and some paper.
拿纸和笔
Write down a name, any name.
写个名字 随便什么名字
Wayne Rigsby.
是Wayne Rigsby
You guessed?
你猜的?
No. Although with that name, it wouldn't be hard to.
不 虽然那个名字也不难猜
I, uh, read your pen.
我 呃 是看着笔顺猜的
So you cheated?
你作弊了?
That's a dirty word.
这次太邪恶了
Maybe just a little.
好吧 的确作了小弊
Well, here's what I think of your little trick.
我给你的小把戏写个评语
I didn't quite get the first word,
我没看清第一个字
but the second word was definitely "you."
但第二个肯定是"你"
Good night.
晚安
Oh, well, that's not very nice.
好吧 这可不是什么好话
-=耐卡影音论坛=-
www.ncar.cc/bbs
谢谢观赏